Guide to the Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
Fries, Waldemar H., Audubon research papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
3427
Waldemar H. Fries b. 1889.
17.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, research material, publications, auction catalogues, exhibition catalogues, art work, books
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, manuscripts, and other materials relating to the writing and production of The Double Elephant Folio; correspondence, slides, books, notebooks,pamphlets and artwork relating to John James Audubon and his family, and other ornithologists. Also, material concerning Audubon exhibitions, including catalogues, Audubon slides, stamps, and photographs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Waldemar Hans Fries graduated from Cornell University in 1911.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, manuscripts, and other materials relating to the writing and production of The Double Elephant Folio; correspondence, slides, books, notebooks,pamphlets and artwork relating to John James Audubon and his family, and other ornithologists. Also, material concerning Audubon exhibitions, including catalogues, Audubon slides, stamps, and photographs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fries, Waldemar H.,b. 1889.; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851.; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851.; Fries, Waldemar H., b. 1889.
Subjects:
Ornithology.; Ornithology--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Color slides.; Notebooks.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
The John James Audubon artwork, collection #6721 also contains original and reproductions of Audubon prints.
NOTES
See also Waldemar H. Fries papers, collection # 47-3-m.849.
SERIES LIST
Series I. American Folios: Correspondence and Notes
Series II. European Folios: Correspondence and Notes
Series III. Collateral Files: Sets in America
Series IV. Collateral Files: Sets outside America
Series V. Correspondence and Notes after 1973
Series VI. Notebooks: Copies of Audubon Letters and Journals, Photographs, Negatives and other Auduboniana
Series VII. Audubon Material
Series VIII. Exhibitions: Catalogues and other Miscellany
Series IX. Auction Catalogues and Price Lists
Series X. Publications and Reviews
Series XI. Art Work (Oversized): Audubon, John James; Audubon, Lucy; DeKay; Edwards; Peale; Wilson
Series XII. Miscellaneous
Separated material, books, publications, etc.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. American Folios: Correspondence and Notes
  - The Academy of Natural Sciences, The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1831, 1839, 1960-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1896, 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Archer Milton Huntington, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Antiquarian Society, 20-22 February, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Artists Cards: The American Museum of Natural History, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The American Museum of Natural History, 1957-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes details of the Elephant Folio, Audubon's "The Birds of America" and a copy of the American Museum Journal, April 1904
  - The American Philosophical Society, 1957-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes manuscripts, proceedings and photographs
  - History of the American Philosophical Society, from The Yearbook for the American Philosophical Society, 1952, and, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sotheby and Co. and Amherst College, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes notes and manuscripts on the folio of the Birds of America at Amherst.
  - Copy of the Liverpool Commercial Chronicle, 15 September, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes manuscripts and museum brochures.
  - Regarding Theodore Anderson, May-June, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Regarding Richard Anderson, 1836-1837; 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Includes copies of letters from John J. Audubon and Richard Anderson.
  - Samuel Appleton, 1853, 1884, 1800s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - James Arnold, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Regarding John Jacob Astor, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes newspaper clippings and carbons.
  - Mill Grove; John John J. Audubon, 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, news clippings, brochures: Audubon State Park, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Laommi Baldwin, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Regarding Mrs. Thomas Barrett, 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and news clipping: Beaufort County Library, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence on Timothy Green Benham, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Frederick W Beinecke, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Includes brochures, information on the Frederick W. Beinecke Set, copy of "The Education of an Explorer: Meriwether Learns to Shoot the Sun", Thomas Jefferson, 1803.
  - Bethany College, 1924, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Includes newspaper clippings and sale information from the Anderson Galleries, 1924.
  - Daniel Blake, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bowdoin College, 1957-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library, and transcripts of letters written by John J. Audubon.
  - Boston Public Library, 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library
  - Boston Society of Natural History (Museum of Science), 1840, 1930, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes reprints of various Museum Bulletins, "Early Days in the Library", and Minutes of the Boston Society of Natural History, 26 February, 1840.
  - Boston Athenaeum, 1833, 1956-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Includes information on the library and Folio plates/prints held there, and copies of letters.
  - James C. H. Bonbright, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reprint: "Reminiscences of John John J. Audubon", by Thomas M Brewer, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Regarding James Brown, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brown University Library, 1970, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Regarding William H Buckler., 1952, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Includes news clippings.
  - Buffalo and Erie County Public Library, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library, and carbon copies of letters to Charles H Williams.
  - Buffalo and Erie County Public Library, 1931, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Includes a list Folio plates/prints held by the library, and a Library Bulletin.
  - Correspondence and Notes: Buffalo Museum, 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter to Buffalo Society of Natural Sciences, 14 October 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The Groton School, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held at there
  - California Academy of Sciences, 1961-1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - California State Library, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Regarding Callet, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence and notes: Carnegie Museum, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the museum
  - Centenary College of Louisiana, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence on Clarence E. Chapman, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Charleston Citizens Private Library, 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Charleston Library Society, 1958-1961, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The Charleston Museum, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Sale Catalogue of John Lewis Childs' Collection, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Charles E. Church and Audubon Shrine., 1957-1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Public Library of Cincinnati and Hamilton County, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library, and copies of correspondence and sale catalogues, 1800s
  - Natural History Museum, Ohio, 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - The City College, New York., 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Regarding Henry Clay Jr., 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Sale Catalogue of William A. Coleman's collections, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - George Dawson Coleman, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - The Taylor Museum Colorado Springs Fine Arts Centre, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Columbia University, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Cooper Union., 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cornell Public Library, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Includes Sales Catalogues and photographs of letters.
  - Cornell University, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library and photographs.
  - List of Audubon items held at Cornell university and other major research library systems, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The John Crerar Library, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library and miscellaneous reprints.
  - Correspondence, notes and information regarding John Croghan, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Regarding Mrs. Theodore Douglas Robinson, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - The Currier Gallery of Art, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Regarding John Perkins Cushings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Dartmouth College library, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library and biographies of Isaac P. Davis.
  - Jean Delacour, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Includes biographies.
  - The Wilmington Society of the Fine Arts, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the society.
  - Henry L. De Rham, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - John Henry Dick, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - James Dickson, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - John Donnell Tilgham, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Duke University, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Regarding Garnett Duncan, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Notes on Correspondence to Enoch Pratt Free Library, 1800s (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Essex Institute, 1957-1974 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Includes notes, newspaper clippings and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the Peabody Library.
  - Daniel W. Evans, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the family
  - Field Museum of Natural History (Chicago), 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Includes photographs, news clippings, copies of manuscripts, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the museum.
  - University of Florida, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Regarding Mrs. C. Ford, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    Includes sale catalogues.
  - Lists: Speaking engagements, Visits to libraries with regard to original subscribers of the Folio, List of Folio sets examined, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Free Library of New Bedford, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Includes brochures, a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library and The Massachussetts Audubon Newsletter, May 1962.
  - Regarding William Gaston Savannah, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Regarding Dr. Eli Geddings, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - University of Georgia, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by their museum
  - Regarding Mrs. Miltone Getz, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Thomas Gilcrease Institute of American History and Art, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Gilmore Roberts, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes transcripts of parts of John J. Audubon's journal.
  - Jay Gould (Estate), 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - William Gowans, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes copies of sale catalogues, 1866.
  - New England Museum, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Regarding James Grimshaw Duncan, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Regarding W. Wilston Gourdin, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes photograph and copies of Gourdin's correspondence, c.1857.
  - J. K. Graves, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Groton School, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ogden Haggerty, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Perry Hall, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Regarding Stephen Alling Halsey, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Regarding Edward Harris, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Copies of John J. Audubon's Correspondence; Copy of "Audubonia" by S. N. Rhoads, 1833-1839, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Harvard University, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library, certificates, and a transcript of John J. Audubon's Journal, 1826.
  - Harvard University, 1959-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Harvard University, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Harvard University Press, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Harvard University: Regarding Joseph Y. Jeanes, 1928-1930, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes copies of Jeanes' letters and Certificates.
  - Haverhill Public Library, 1957-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Vanderbilt University: Alexander Heard, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Regarding Edward Heckscher, 1962, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - James Jeane Hill Reference Library, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Edward E. Hills, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by him
  - Henry Hitchcock, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Regarding Major Robert Hopkins, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Mr. Ralph Hornblower, 1958, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Regarding John C Hubbard, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Regarding J. J. Hughes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Regarding Mobile, Alaska, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1957-1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - University of Illinois, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - The Indiana Historical Society, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Indiana University, 1957-1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Includes a copy of the Book Collector, Vol 6, 1957, photographs and a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library.
  - Regarding Patrick Tracy Jackson, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Johns Hopkins Library, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Regarding Johnson Grace Phillips., 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by her.
  - Regarding Philip S. Johnson, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - H.D. Johnson, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - George G. Kalbach, 1959, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - University of Kansas, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Regarding William H. Kemble, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Includes copies of sales catalogoues.
  - University of Kentucky, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Regarding James Gore King, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Regarding Thomas Butler King, 1920s, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Includes transcripts of King's letters and copies of "Altama Plantation" by Margaret Davis Cate.
  - Dr. Walter K. Kluckauf, 1957-1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Laval University, Quebec, 1957-1961, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Includes vol. XXVI of "Les Carnets de Zoologie", 1966, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library. Also a list of complete sets of Birds of America in the U.S. and Canada along with a letter to Antonoio Drolet, librarian ta Laval University.
  - Notes regarding Alexander Lawson: copy of the Penn Monthly, June 1879, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Legislative Library, Fredericton, 1957-1970 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Includes a copy of "The Audubon Mystery" by Boone and Gammon, in The Atlantic Advocate, March 1959, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Lehigh University, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Lenox Library, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Library Association of Portland, 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - The Library of Congress, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Includes news clippings, Report of the Librarian of Congress, 1946, transcripts of John J. Audubon's letters, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Library of Congress: War Department Copy., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Library of Congress: War Department Copy, 1960-1971 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Includes copies of the Library of Congress Information Bulletin, October 1970, and D.C. Libraries, July 1995 Also includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - The Library of Congress, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Includes photographs of letters and certificates
  - Library of Parliament, Ottawa, 1957-1974 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    Includes transcripts of John J. Audubon's journal, photographs and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Linda Hall Library, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - The Long Island Historical Society, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - The Linnean Society of London, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Louisiana State Museum, 1957-1-1963 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Includes sale deeds, brochures and news clippings
  - Louisiana State University, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Cornelius C. Low, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Albert E. Lownes, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Includes photographs, copies of news articles, Brown: Alumni Monthly, July 1970, and a copy of "Ten Audubon Letters" by Lownes, and a listing of Lownes' Folio set
  - Lyceum of Natural History, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Logan MacCoy, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Dr. Walter McCoy, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by him.
  - Macy's, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Canada Steamship Lines; Public Archives of Canada, 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the Archives and a copy of "Catalogue of The Manoir Richelieu Collection of Candiana, 1930
  - McGill University, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    Includes brochures, a copy of "An Introduction to the Literature of Vertebrate Zoology", 1931, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Regarding Dr. Henry McMurtrie, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - David H. March, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Regarding Edward Martin, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Bradley H. Martin., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Includes copies of "The Book Collector", Autumn 1963 and a list of Folio plates/prints held by him.
  - Maryland Historical Society, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - State Library of Maryland, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    Includes copies and photographs of John J. Audubon's, and related, correspondence (1833-139), and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Library of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Mechanics' Institute Library, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Regarding Paul Mellon, 1957-1969 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    Includes photographs, a list of Folio plates/prints held by him, and also a list of sets in Europe.
  - Regarding the Mercantile Library, New York, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Includes photographs.
  - Theo A. Merkt, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Regarding Adams H. Merrill, 1959-1969 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Regarding Thomas Metcalf, 1957, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the museum.
  - University of Michigan, 1957-1972 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    Includes a copy of a dissertation on the early history of their library and a list of Folio plates/prints held by it.
  - Milwaukee Public Library, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Minneapolis Athenaeum, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library.
  - University of Minnesota, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Audubon House, Florida, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    Includes catalogues, news clipping, a transcript of John H. Baker's speech at the dedication of the Audubon House(1960) and a list of Folio plates/prints held there.
  - Regarding John David Mongin, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Regarding John B. Morriss, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Museum of Science and Space Transit Planetarium, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Regarding George Hewitt Myers, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints originally held by him.
  - Regarding N. C. Nash, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Regarding Natchez, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1958-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes news clippings and a copy of "Biographical Memoir of John Campbell Merriam".
  - National Gallery of Art, 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes a copy of "Black Diamond Express", May 1900, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the gallery.
  - Regarding John Neal, 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Includes a copy of "Audubon, Joseph R. Mason and John Neal", American literature, May 1934.
  - New Brunswick Theological Seminary, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - New York Botanical Garden, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the Garden.
  - Newbury Library, Chicago, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - New York Historical Society, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The New York Public Library, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Includes news clippings, sale deeds and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - New York Public Library: Listing and Notes on the Astor Set, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - New York Public Library: Listing and Notes on the Lenox Set, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - New York Public Library: Listing and Notes on Stuart, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New York Public Library: Listing and Notes on Samuel Tilden's set, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - New York Public Library: Listing and Notes on Lenox No. 2, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - New York Society Library, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - North Carolina State Library, 1959-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - R. W. Norton Art Gallery, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Includes transcripts and photographs of James Audubon's correspondence, 1830s
  - The Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes calendars of Audubon paintings, 1951-1956, 1958
  - Northwestern University, 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - R.W Norton Art Gallery, 1958-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Regarding Dr. Hallen Nutt, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes news clippings
  - Regarding William Oakes, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Includes a brochure of The Victoria Mansion, Portland, and a copy of the Maine Field Naturalist, July, 1957
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Oberlin College Library, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Regarding John Jay Paul, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Peabody Institute, Baltimore, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by the institute.
  - Peabody Institute, Peabody, 1957-1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Includes photographs and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Peabody Museum, Salem, 1958-1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miss Clara C. Peck, 1958-1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Regarding Thomas Perkins, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Includes transcripts and photographs of John J. Audubon's correspondence, 1831- 1832
  - William Perry, 1959, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Regarding Samuel J. Peters, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Regarding Alfred F. Pflaumer, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Regarding Evan Poultey, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Phillips Academy, 1957-1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The Pierpoint Morgan Library, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Includes sale catalogues and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Darlington memorial Library, University of Pittsburgh, 1958-1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - The Plantation Parade, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Includes a copy of pages 285-305 of "The Plantation Parade: The grand Manner on Louisiana", 1945
  - Regarding James Potter, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Includes news clippings and pages 209-211 of The Princeton University Chronicle, Spring 1964
  - Nathanial Potter, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Includes a copy of "John James Audubon's Baltimore Physician Patrons", Bulletin, University of Maryland, January 1964.
  - George W. Pratt, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Edward Prince, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - John Dynely Prince, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 45)